<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the Honourable the knights, citizens and burgesses in Parliament assembled, the humble petition of Percivall Brunskell, Gent.</title>
            <author>Brunskell, Percivall, 17th cent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A29927</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B5236A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R3862</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11791463</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11791463</idno>
            <idno type="VID">49218</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A29927)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 49218)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 17:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the Honourable the knights, citizens and burgesses in Parliament assembled, the humble petition of Percivall Brunskell, Gent.</title>
                  <author>Brunskell, Percivall, 17th cent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication from Wing.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Charles --  II, --  King of England, 1630-1685.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:49218:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>To the Honourable the Knights, Citizens and Burgeſſes in Parliament Aſſembled,</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> Percivall Brunskell, <hi>Gent.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>THAT King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, and his Now Majeſty, were Bountifully Inclined to Your Petitioner; but ſuch as were Intruſted to fulfil Their Majeſties Pleaſure, neglected your Petitioner: And your Petitioner being ſent to Parliament, his Caſe, with the Committees Reſolutions thereon, and the Reports, Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nions and Certificates of Learned Men in the Late Reigns and This, Repreſenting your Petitioner Worthy of Reward, were laid before the Late Houſe, 27 <hi>December</hi> 1690. And ſeveral Laws are ſince Made, and others have been on the Stage for Redreſs of Abuſes, particularly ſet forth in your Petitioner's Caſe. And Laſt Seſſion your Petitioner's Caſe was Re-Examined and Reported worthy the Conſideration of the Houſe; and the Honourable Committee Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved and Reported their Reſolutions, <hi>That the Houſe be moved, That an Humble Addreſs be made to His Majeſty, That He would be Graciouſly pleaſed to take into His Princely Conſideration the Services and Sufferings of your Petitioner, and Reward the ſame:</hi> But the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port being made the 20th Day of <hi>April</hi> laſt, juſt at the ending of the Seſſion, and when the Houſe was Buſily Employed to find out Perſons ſuſpected to be Guilty of Bribery, the Sad Effects of Buy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and Selling Offices, and Places of Truſt and Profit, to which all Miſcarriages by Sea and Land-may be imputed. Your Petitio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner was dropt and remains a poor Petitioner, ſtript of all his own Eſtate and Practice, plunged 3000 <hi>l.</hi> in Debt, which Increaſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>h eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Year 180 <hi>l.</hi> for want of Something to pay off either Principal or Intereſt, and is forced to Abſcond, ſo that he cannot work for his own and Families Subſiſtence, and hath gotten Nothing after Long Attendance and Dependance, but what will not pay off Tradeſmen
<pb facs="tcp:49218:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>to give him Credit for his own and Families Neceſſaries. And tho' Offices become Void daily, wherein your Petitioner may be Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viceable to His Majeſty, and His People, and Pay Debts, and make Proviſion for himſelf and Family: And although all that Love and Honour His Majeſty, Agree, That your Petitioner's Afflictions have rather Improved than Impaired him for the Service of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, yet your Petitioner is neglected, whereby his Oppreſſion is greater than Tongue or Pen can expreſs.</p>
            <p>Now for as much as all in ſuch Imployments as your Petitioner was in, are obliged to take Oaths which enjoin them to make Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coveries and Propoſals for the Service of the Publick, as your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner hath done, Oaths being all the Security the People have, That the Laws ſhall be duly and impartially Executed, without which the People cannot be Maintained and Defended in their Rights, Liberties and Properties: Your Petitioner hopes that the Parents of the Law will not ſuffer him to Languiſh under Oppreſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, for obeying Lawful Commands.</p>
            <p>Your Petitioner therefore moſt Humbly prays this Honourable Houſe to take his Sad and Deplorable Caſe into Conſideration, That he may be Relieved as to your Honours may ſeem Meet and Juſt:</p>
            <closer>And your Petitioner, as in Duty Bound, ſhall Ever Pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
